Guide to the World War I Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
World War I collection
1914-1983
1914-1919
MS 754
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
13.5
(20 boxes)
An artificial collection of printed material, photographs, songs, reports, correspondence, diaries, and miscellanea of United States men, many with a Yale University connection, relating to World War I, 1914-1919.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The bulk of the printed material was transferred from the Edward House Papers. Other material has either been the gift of various donors or transferred from other collections.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Related Material
Edward M. House Papers, MS 466. Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series and nine additions: I. Reports, Memoranda, and Printed Matter, 1914-1922. II. Personal Papers, 1914-1983.
Scope and Contents
The core of the material in this collection was originally assembled out of the files of the Colonel Edward M. House collection in Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library. It has been added to by subsequent gifts from various donors.
The collection consists of miscellaneous printed matter, photographs, songs, reports, and a small amount of correspondence and diaries of American men, chiefly with a Yale connection, describing their war experiences. Many of the printed items are official reports by the Belgian, British, French and German governments. Also included are special issues of illustrated magazines and memoirs of the war. Of the thirty-nine war songs in the collection, twenty-eight are in English and eleven are in French. These are in the form of sheet music and contain both lyrics and piano accompaniment. Among the reports are a history of the American military government in occupied Germany, 1918-1920 by Colonel I. L. Hunt, edited by Truman Smith, and a synopsis of the history of the European Service Division of the American Expeditionary Forces by Bryan F. Peters.
Photographs and maps marked with battle plans offer detailed information on the way the war was fought. Of particular interest is a nine-volume photographic account of the war prepared by the Section Photographique de l'Armée Française, aerial photographs of French territory showing battle lines, and two photograph albums assembled by M. G. H. Nettleton. German naval operations are illustrated with printed matter, broadsides, etchings showing naval battles and naval heroes, music and memorabilia.
For posters issued by France, Germany, Great Britain and the United States, see the War Poster Collection, MS 671.
World War, 1914-1918 -- Atrocities; World War, 1914-1918 -- Equipment and supplies; World War, 1914-1918 -- Participation, Foreign; World War, 1914-1918 -- Pictorial works; World War, 1914-1918 -- Songs and music; World War, 1914-1918; Photographs; House, Edward Mandell, 1858-1938
- Reports, Memoranda, and Printed Matter, 1914-1922; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  A collection of miscellaneous printed matter relating to German naval operations during World War I. Included are colored broadsides (in French and German) and etchings showing naval battles, government posters, music, prints of naval heroes, an album of cartoons, and a collection of thirty-three "Vivant" ribbons. Also in the series are selected issues of periodicals devoted to naval events. These are listed individually below.
  - German naval operations, 1914-1919
    - An Flanderns Küste. Kriegszeitung für das Marinekorps: Nr. 9, 1916 July 15 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Berliner Illustrirte Zeitung
      - 26.Jahrgang, Nr. 12, "U-Boot-Nummer", 1917 March 17 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 26.Jahrgang, Nr. 24, "U-Boot-Nummer", 1917 June 17 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Deutschland zur See
      - Heft 11, seite 3-4 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Heft 27, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Illustrirte Zeitung
      - Nr. 3762, Kriegsnummer 53, 1915 August 15 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Nr. 3863, Kriegsnummer 154, 1917 July 12 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Innsbrucker Kriegsflugblätter: No. 228, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Kriegszeit Künstlerflugblätter
      - No. 26, 1915 February 10 (Box 1A, Folder 1)
      - No. 39, 1915 May 12 (Box 1A, Folder 1)
    - Kriegszeitung der Festung Borkum
      - Nr. 31, 1916 March 4 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Nr. 38, 1916 April 22 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Leipziger Zeitung. Sonder-Ausgabe, 1914 August 2, 27 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Simplicissimus: 21.Jahrgang, Nr. 51, 1917 March 20 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Kriegsflugblätter des Simplicissimus: Nos. 9, 14, 15, 18, 20, 22, 26, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Der Stosstrupp: 1.Jahrgang, Nr. 36, 1917 July 28 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wachtfeuer. Künstlerblätter zum Krieg
      - Nr. 5, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Nr. 108, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wieland: Nr. 7, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Zeebrügger Tageblatt
      - "Einmalige Sonder-Ausgabe", 1916 December 31 (Box 1A, Folder 2)
      - 1917 April 1 (Box 1A, Folder 2)
      - "Jahreszeitung für Humorersatz", 1917 December 31 (Box 1A, Folder 2)
    - "Die Torpedierung der 'Gambetta'", Circa 1916 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - "Lusitania" clipping, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Naval illustrations, Circa 1914 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Sheet music, Circa 1915 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Memorabilia
    - Certificate for Mather Almon Abbott, signed by Josephus Daniels, Secretary of the Navy, 1920 (Box 1A, Folder 3)
    - "Vivant" ribbons and armbands, Circa 1916 (Box 1A, Folder 8)
  - Portraits
    - AVEC LA 1re DIVISION AMERICAINE SUR LE FRONT from the Album de 16 croquis lithographies pris sur le front am é ricaine en France, for L. Jonas
      - "Un Lieutenant (X...)" (Box 1A, Folder 3)
      - Portrait of an American Expeditionary Force trooper (Box 1A, Folder 3)
      - Portrait of a motorcycle driver (Box 1A, Folder 3)
      - Portrait of a lieutenant, 20th Infantry, American Expeditionary Force, mounted (Box 1A, Folder 3)
      - "Le Spleen" (Box 1A, Folder 3)
      - Portrait of a group of soldiers conversing (Box 1A, Folder 3)
      - "Attendant la soupe" (Box 1A, Folder 3)
      - "Major commandant de bataillon de la 26eme division" (Box 1A, Folder 3)
    - Portrait of soldier, wearing Y.M.C.A. insignia. France [lithograph], 1918 (Box 1A, Folder 3)
    - Portrait of unidentified man. Signed, on plate, Walter Tittle [engraving] (Box 1A, Folder 3)
    - Portrait of unidentified military officer. Signed, Walter Tittle [engraving], 1922 January 25 (Box 1A, Folder 3)
  - Printed matter
    - "The G.A.F." (The Gazette of the Archangel Force) [first number published weekly by the British Archangel Expeditionary Force for the British troops, Archangel, Russia (Accession 94-M-21)], 1919 June 7 (Box 1A, Folder 4)
    - Wallgren, Abian A. Wally. His cartoons of the A.E.F. (Paris, The Stars and Stripes) [54 leaves illustrated], 1919 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - L'Illustration: No. 3950-3951, 1918 November 16-23 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - L'Illustration: No. 3957 [pp. 11-14. Showing effects of bombardment in Paris and armistice celebrations in Alsace-Lorraine], 1919 January 4 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - L'Illustration: No. 3985-3986 [84 p. Special issue devoted to the victory celebrations in Paris], 1919 July 19-26 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 10 miscellaneous American posters and brochures by ministers or on religious subjects, Circa 1918 (Box 1A, Folder 5)
    - German atrocities on record. With authentic illustrations. Reprinted from the Field. London, 1915 February 13 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Illustrated memoir of the world war. New Haven, CT: National Publishing Co. [40 p.], 1930 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Honolulu Star-Bulletin, 1918 November 11 (Box 1A, Folder 6)
    - Pacific Commercial Advertiser [Honolulu], 1918 November 11 (Box 1A, Folder 6)
    - Broadsides and flyers on war loans, politics, morale, etc., 1914-1918 (Box 1A, Folder 7)
    - 1917. Documents de la section photographique de l'armée française. Paris, Emile Paul, 9 v. [Captions to the photographs in French, English, Portuguese and Spanish] (Box 2)
    - Fragments from France, Parts 1, 2, 5, by Capt. Bruce Bairnsfather, 1918, undated (Box 2)
    - The Home Sector, 1919 September 20, December 13 (Box 2)
    - Scrapbook of German and British cartoons, compiled by Lisbeth Krause, 1915, undated (Box 2)
  - War songs-sheet music [listed by composer]
    - Baskette, Billy. Good-bye Broadway, hello France. Words by C. Francis Reisner and Benny Davis. New York, Leo. Feist, Inc. [for voice and piano], 1917 (Box 2)
    - Berlin, Irving, and Edgar Leslie, George W. Meyer. Let's all be Americans now. New York, Waterson, Berlin & Snyder Co., 1917 (Box 2)
    - Berlin, Irving. Over the Sea Boys. New York, Waterson, Berlin & Snyder Co., 1917 (Box 2)
    - Cohan, George M. Over there. New York, Wm. Jerome Publishing Co. [with colored photograph of William J. Reilly, U.S.N. on cover], 1917 (Box 2)
    - Elliott, Zo. There's a Long, Long Trail. Words by Stoddard King. New York, M. Witmark & Sons, 1914 (Box 2)
    - Fairman, George. I don't know where I'm going, but I'm on my way. New York, Harry von Tilzer Music Publishing Co., 1917 (Box 2)
    - Flynn, Allan J. There's a green hill out in Flanders (there's a green hill up in Maine). New York, Al. Piantadosi & Co. Inc., 1917 (Box 2)
    - Goetz, Goleman and Jack Stern. We're going to celebrate the end of the war in ragtime. (Be sure that Woodrow Wilson leads the band). New York, Shapiro, Berstein & Co., 1915 (Box 2)
    - Howard, Joseph E. Somewhere in France is the lily. Lyrics by Philander Johnson. New York, M. Witmark & Sons, 1917 (Box 2)
    - Jerrald, Charles J. The Wilson-Lincoln reign, 1915-1861. Words by R. Bruce Grey. Grand Forks, N.D., Stone Music Co. (Box 2)
    - Jerome, M. K. Just a baby's prayer at Twilight (for her daddy over there). New York, Waterson, Berlin & Snyder Co., 1917 (Box 2)
    - Judge, Jack and Harry Williams. It's a long, long way to Tipperary. New York, Chappel & Co., 1912 (Box 2)
    - Lange, Arthur. America here's my boy. The sentiment of every American mother. Words by Andrew B. Sterling. New York, Joe Morris Music Co., 1917 (Box 2)
    - McCarron, Charles R. and Carey Morgan. I'm glad I can make you cry. New York, Joseph W. Stern & Co., 1918 (Box 2)
    - Merrill, Blanche. We take our hats off to you-Mr. Wilson. New York, Leo Feist, 1914 (Box 2)
    - Mohr, Halsey K. Liberty Bell (It's time to ring again). Words by Joe Goodwin. New York, Shapiro, Bernstein & Co., 1917 (Box 2)
    - Nelson, Ed. When Yankee Doodle learns to "Parlez vous Français." Words by William Hart. New York, A. J. Stasny Music Co., 1917 (Box 2)
    - Perlman, Morris. If the Kaiser were wiser he'd keep far away. Words by Pete Kramer and Jack Singer. New York, Perlman, Corn Publishing Co., 1917 (Box 2)
    - Piantadosi, Al. I didn't raise my boy to be a soldier. A mother's plea for peace. Lyrics by Alfred Bryan. New York, Leonard Feist, 1915 (Box 2)
    - Rice, Gitz
      - Lieutenant. Keep your head down. (Allemand, Fritzie Boy). New York, Leonard Feist, Inc. [with autograph by Gitz Rice on the cover], 1918 (Box 2)
      - We stopped tham at the Marne (It's to___ with Germany). New York, Leonard Feist, Inc. [with autograph by Gitz Rice on the cover], 1918 (Box 2)
      - You can't drive my dreams away. Boston, Oliver Ditson Company, 1919 (Box 2)
    - Sterling, Andrew B., Bernie Grossman & Arthur Lange. We're going over. New York, Joe Morris Music Co., 1917 (Box 2)
    - Von Tilzer, Albert. Honey bo y. Words by Jack Norworth. New York, The York Music Co., 1917 (Box 2)
    - Wescott, D. Run the hun. New York, Plaza Music Company, 1918 (Box 2)
    - Wells, Jack. J oan of Arc they are calling you. Words by Alfred Bryan and Willie Weston. New York, Waterson, Berlin & Snyder Co., 1917 (Box 2)
    - Woodruff, Joseph. After the war is over. Words by E. J. Pourmon and Andrew B. Sterling New York, Joe Morris Music Co., 1918 (Box 2)
    - Speaks, Oley. When the boys come home. Words by John Hay. New York, G. Schirmer, 1917 (Box 2)
    - Darien, Jules et Eugène Poncin. Mam'zell' la Victoire. Marche Française. Paroles de Pierre Chapelle. Paris, Aux Melodies Nouvelles [Edition exclusive pour la Rue], 1917 (Box 2)
    - Paris-Concert No. 2 Willems. Paris, Edition Belge Willems [a collection of six songs, with words and music. "The Madelon of Victory" in both French and English], 1918 (Box 2)
    - Quand Madelon.... Paris, L. Bousquet (Musique Militaire par Allier) [a collection of three songs with words and music], 1918 (Box 2)
    - Planquette, R. Le Régiment de Sambre & Meuse. Paris, C. Joubert, undated (Box 2)
  - Rationing: printed matter
    - France: rationing applications, books, stamps, 1918-1919 (Box 3)
    - Germany
      - German war photographs (Box 3)
      - Illustrations relating to the war and war heroes (Box 3)
      - Ten programs: Deutsches Theater, Lille [from the House Papers], 1916, 1918 (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous printed matter (Box 3)
    - Great Britain
      - Correspondence Respecting the European Crisis... August, 1914 [Cd. 746] (Box 3)
      - Rationing forms, applications, notices (Box 3)
      - Specimen ration books (Box 3)
      - Posters regarding rationing, food conservation (Box 3)
    - International Red Cross: reports on British prison camps, India and Burma; Isle of Man (Box 3)
    - Italy: rationing forms (Box 3)
    - Mandel, Lafayette B.
      - Memoranda, notes for talks on food and diet; printed matter; memorabilia [transferred to the Lafayette Mendel Papers, MS 1146] (Box 3)
      - Correspondence from Herbert Hoover and F. C. Walcott regarding Inter-Allied Food Commission [transferred to the Lafayette Mendel Papers, MS 1146], 1918 January 15, November 2 (Box 3)
    - Poulbot, Francisque, Des Gosses et des Bonhommes: cent dessins et deux lettres, Paris, Publiépar l'auteur, [1917] (Box 3)
    - United States
      - The Mess Kit. Published for the soldiers of the A.E.F., France. Vol. 1, No. 1, 1919 June (Box 3)
      - Ration books, menus, pamphlets (Box 3)
    - War poetry: French and English (Box 3)
  - Photographs
    - Aerial
      - Mortier Ravine to Vauguois (altitude 900 m.) (Box 4)
      - Vauguois to Malancourt (altitude 900 m.) (Box 4)
      - Vauguois to Malancourt (altitude 300 m.) (Box 4)
      - Malancourt to Meuse River (altitude 300 m.) (Box 4)
      - Bois Carréto Cheppy (altitude 300 m.) (Box 4)
    - Paris sous les Bombardements
      - Album showing Versailles and Camp d'Aviation de Villacoublay (Box 4)
      - Album and loose photographs of inspections at Ecole de Châteaureux (Box 4)
  - Maps
    - VI Army-Manoury [showing lines of battle] (Box 4)
    - Metz area Meuse Argonne Offensive, Paris [showing battle positions] (Box 4)
  - Memorabilia
    - Menu-Christmas dinner for President Wilson, Montigny-le-Roi, 1918 (Box 4)
    - Travel memorabilia-telegram, tickets, France, 1918 (Box 4)
    - Ticket to Allied women war workers' mass meeting, Paris, [1918?] (Box 4)
    - U.S. patriotic stamps, 1917 (Box 4)
    - Liberty Loan buttons, undated (Box 4)
    - Cartoon by Lor Vac showing the Kaiser as a stage prompter [original ink drawing on paper mounted on board], undated (Box 4)
  - Printed matter
    - American publications, including educational material for troops in France (Box 5)
    - British publications (Box 5)
    - French publications (Box 5)
    - German publications (Box 5)
    - Swedish publications (Box 5)
    - Italian and Russian publications (Box 5)
  - British command papers [regarding prisoners of war, internment camps, and German atrocities in Africa], 1914-1918 (Box 6)
  - U.S. Army papers: Hunt, I. L., "The American Military Government of Occupied Germany, 1918-1920." Report of Col. I. L. Hunt, Officer in charge of Civil Affairs, 3rdArmy and American Forces in Germany. Edited by Truman Smith
    - Volume 1. American military government of occupied Germany, 1918-1920 [including miscellaneous clippings and a speech, "Some principles of military government," by Col. Hunt] (Box 7)
    - Volume 2. German and Prussian government; studies in military government (Box 8)
    - Volume 3. American policies in occupied territories (Box 9)
    - Volume 4. Rules and regulation of the American Army of Occupation [miscellaneous items relating to American occupation of Germany; vital statistics of Germany, 1909-1919] (Box 10)
- Personal Papers, 1914-1983; Series II
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1914-1919 (Box 11, Folder 1 - 3)
  - Volume of telegraph dispatches, translated into English from the French, 1914-1915 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Peters, Bryan Forman, 1890-, Y. 1913
    - Synopsis of "History of European Service Division," American Expeditionary Forces [typescript, 119 p.], Circa 1919 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Collection of transport and miscellaneous memoranda (typewritten) relating to the American Expeditionary Forces, 1918-1919 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Pruden, Russell Godine, 1883-1949, Y. 1906 [diary, transferred to Pruden Family Papers, Mss 406]
  - Ewing, George Washington, Jr., 1891-1918, Y. 1915
    - Correspondence, 1917-1918, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Newspapers, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Ewing, Lewis R., d. 1918
    - Correspondence, 1917-1919, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Aviation Section, Signal Corps: notes, map, printed matter, 1917-1918, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Smith, Robinson, 1876-1954, Y. 1898: "Anecdotes sur L'Occupation": personal narratives, in French, collected by Smith, 1918-1919, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - American Red Cross: printed report, The Work of the American Red Cross During the War, 1919 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Foch, Ferdinand, 1851-1929
    - Autographed copy of orders, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Printed portrait, undated
  - Hann, George Rice, 1889-, Y. 1913: correspondence [typed copies], 1918 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Bowerman, Guy Emerson, Jr., 1896-1947, Y. 1920 [non-graduate]
    - Diary, 1917-1918 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Diary, with printed matter, 1918, 1947, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Diary (published copy), The Compensations of War: The Diary of an Ambulance Driver during the Great War, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Belgium-German Occupation, 1914-1918 [anonymous description of conditions], undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Engineer Officer's Training School, Camp Humphreys, Virginia [list of Yale graduates enrolled], 1918 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Thirteen postcards depicting scenes of damage to buildings in France during World War I, 1914-1916 (Box 12, Folder 20)
- Additional Material, Accession 1990-M-048
  - Scrapbook of over 300 dispatches from Headquarters 51stInfantry Brigade, American Expeditionary Forces, 26thDivision Message Center, France; includes 29 messages regarding terrain exercises, 1918 October 23-November 1, 1919 January 8 (Box 13)
  - Document approving the annexation of Fiume (chief seaport of Hungary before World War I, also spelled Rieka) to Italy with a "free-port" status [signed by the mayor and heads of commercial and industrial firms of Fiume and sent to Gabriele d'Annunzio, Chief in Command of Fiume], 1919 October 11 (Box 13)
  - Cover letter of Herbert Adams Gibbons which accompanied a copy of historian H. Iorga's discourse before the Romanian Chamber of Deputies on 1916 Dec 27, 1917 August 4 (Box 13)
  - Journal containing reminiscences of the formation and role of the Royal Marine Brigade in the early phases of World War I [with newspaper clipping], [1914?] (Box 13)
  - Letter, Captain Walter Camp, Jr. to Robert E. Wald describing life on the front lines with the Allied Expeditionary Force, 1918 August 5 (Box 13)
- Additional Material, Accession 1992-M-002
  See Accession 1990-M-048
- Additional Material, Accession 1992-M-086
- Additional Material, Accession 1993-M-062
- Additional Material, Accession 1996-M-083
- Additional Material, Circa 1916-1931; Accession 1996-M-098
  This addition consists of a scrapbook, ca. 1916-1918, belonging to Amelia ("Amy") Leavitt Hill, documenting her trip to France and England. The scrapbook has been disassembled and the material separated into folders of letters, memorabilia, newspaper clippings, photographs, and postcards. Correspondence consists of telegrams and letters in English and French, some from French soldiers, regarding Hill's trip and describing their experiences in World War I. Other material relates to Hill's ocean voyage, her stay in Europe, and the progress of the war. There are also a few newspaper clippings from the post-war period.
  - Correspondence, 1916-1918 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Memorabilia, Circa 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1916-1931, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, Circa 1916 (Box 1, Folder 4 - 5)
  - Postcards, Circa 1916-1918 (Box 1, Folder 6 - 7)
- Additional Material, Accession 1997-M-011
  - France
    - "On to Berlin" [handbill in English and French], 1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - American E. F. University [program for Mother's Day service held at "America's first university on foreign soil"], 1919 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Ration stamps, 1919, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Commission Américaine de Préservation contre la Tuberculose en France [brochures and postcard on the prevention of tuberculosis], undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Germany: proclamation in German by Field Marshall Archduke Friedrich [contains text of a letter from Emperor Franz Joseph to Archduke Friedrich concerning the former's wearing of the Military Service Cross, First Class], 1915 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Italy: "Carta Corografica della Albania", 1918 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - United States
    - Handy Book for the Hospital Corps: United States Navy [prepared under the direction of the Surgeon General], 1914 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Washington, D.C. [street plan by United States Geological Survey], 1918 August (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - France Our Ally: A Brief Account of France, Its People, and Their Part in the War, with Special Information for American Soldiers, by B. Van Vorst, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Hay, Kenneth Brown [non-graduate of the Class of 1917; died in France on Thanksgiving Day, 1917 Nov 29]
    - Diary [includes calling cards and notes laid in], 1915-1917, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Dried flowers from memorial service, 1917 December 9 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Obituaries, 1917 December (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Additional Material, Accession 1997-M-044
  General note
  See Accession 1997-M-011, Box 1, folders 10-12
- Additional Material, Accession 1999-M-100
  - American Ambulance Field Service: photographs taken in France [includes Yale graduates], 1915-1916 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Deutsche Soldaten" [flyer in German with French translation exhorting German soldiers to cease fighting], 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional Material, Accession 2005-M-009
  - Pamphlets on the European War
    - Cooper, Bessie
      - Carnet d'étranger, 1916 August 11 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - "Sauf-conduit pour les personnes voyageant...", 1916 August 26 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Permis de séjour à un étranger, 1916 July 17 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "National Ration Book", 1918 October 21 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Picture postcards of World War, 1914-1918
    - Avant et Après la Destruction d'Ypres, [ca. 1914-1918] (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "European War, 1914-, Postcards", 1914-[1918] (Box 1, Folder 6 - 7)
    - "Picture Postcards of European War," Raphael Tuck and Sons, 1914-[1918] (Box 1, Folder 8 - 9)
  - Photographs furnished by Elliott Service Company, New York [69 photographs, most with descriptions], [1914-1917] (Box 2–3)